msudenver.edu 2019-12-24

# Privacy Statement | Privacy Statement | MSU Denver

Metropolitan State University of Denver is committed to ensuring the privacy and accuracy of all confidential information. The University does not actively share personal information gathered from Web servers. However, because MSU Denver is a public institution, some information collected from the MSU Denver website, including the summary server log information, e-mail sent to the website, and information collected from Web-based forms, may be subject to the Open Records policy. This means that while information is not actively shared, in some cases the University may be compelled by law to release information gathered from Web servers.

As part of the University commitment to maintaining the privacy of Web users, MSU Denver has developed this privacy statement. The statement has two purposes:

Metropolitan State University of Denver complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which prohibits the release of education records other than public directory information, without student permission. For additional details on FERPA, the document is available for review at [www.ed.gov/offices/OII/fpco/ferpa/](http://www.ed.gov/offices/OII/fpco/ferpa/).

The MSU Denver Web consists of numerous Web servers. Some servers, sites and services hosted by non-IT departments may have individual privacy statements.  However, such policies must be reviewed by the appropriate authorities and must be posted on their servers. Such policies must adhere to all federal and state regulations.

The MSU Denver website contains links to hundreds of external websites and services. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of external websites.

 **Information Collected**  
The University Web servers generate temporary logs that contain the following information:

The log data is used by system administrators and web content managers to tune the website for efficiency and is not ordinarily associated with specific individuals. See Responsible Use of Information Technology Resources Policy for further information ([www.msudenver.edu/technology/policies/](http://www.msudenver.edu/technology/policies/ "Policies"))  
Summary reports produced from the logs help web publishers determine what pages are most popular. For example, the aggregate reports can show each page accessed and how many times it was viewed. The reports can also show what times of the day and what days of the week are most popular and from where the web users are accessing the Internet.

 **Personal Information**  
The University does not collect personal information on individuals unless they voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information. For instance, some MSU Denver websites may request personal information such as name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number to provide certain services.  Any personally identifiable information - sent to us will be used only for the purpose indicated and only the information necessary to complete the transaction will be collected.  MSU Denver will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information without consent, except to the extent required by law.  This extends to the collection of all personally identifiable information, regardless of the source or medium.

 **Cookies**  
Cookies are small pieces of data stored by the Web browser. Cookies are often used to remember information about preferences and pages users have visited. For example, when visiting some sites on the Web a  "Welcome Back" message may appear. The first time the site was visited, a cookie was likely set on the computer. When the user returns to the address, the cookie is read again. Users can refuse to accept cookies, can disable cookies, and remove cookies from the hard drive. Please see you're the appropriate Web browser provider's help documentation for instructions how to do this.

Various MSU Denver Web servers use cookies in different ways.  The University's portal system uses cookies so individuals will not have to repeatedly enter user names and passwords when going to different areas of the student information system. This login process uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) so the user name and password are encrypted between the Web browser and the University Web server.

Some Web servers within the University may also use cookies to retain user preference information. It is against University policy to share this information with external third parties.

 **Security and Accuracy of Confidential Information**   
The University does its best to ensure that the personal information retained about individuals is accurate. Every faculty member, staff member and student has the ability to check and update personal information such as his or her name, address, phone, etc. online at the [Student Hub](http://www.msudenver.edu/studenthub) or the [Faculty and Staff page](http://www.msudenver.edu/facstaff/).

Although no computer system is 100% secure, MSU Denver has deployed extensive security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information under University control.

 **E-commerce & Revenue Generation**  
Several sites within MSU Denver enable users to pay for products or services online with a credit card. Unless otherwise noted, these transactions are encrypted using SSL technology. It is University policy that confidential information entered in the transaction is used only for the purpose described in that transaction, unless an additional use is specifically stated on that site.

 **Sharing of Information**  
MSU Denver does, upon explicit request of users, share information with other parties and gather information from other private data providers. For example, the University receives test scores from testing agencies and will send transcripts to other schools. This is done only at the request of users (persons to whom the information applies).

Consistent with FERPA, the University does not release personal student information, other than public directory information, to other parties unless an explicit written authorization is submitted requesting the institution to do so.  Students who wish to have their information removed from the campus directory should visit the Registrar's Office in Student Success Building 160.

 **Open Records Requests**  
Except for educational records governed by FERPA, all information collected from the University website, including the summary server log information, e-mail sent to the website, and information collected from Web-based forms, may be made available to requesting parties if it is subject to the Colorado Open Records Act.

 **Comments and Feedback**  
Send comments to [webteam@msudenver.edu](mailto:webteam@msudenver.edu).  When sending comments, include a current mailing address. Do not send attachments with the message. 

NOTE:  DUE TO OUR CONCERN ABOUT COMPUTER VIRUSES AND THE DAMAGE THEY CAUSE, E-MAIL MESSAGES CONTAINING ATTACHMENTS WILL BE DELETED WITHOUT OPENING.
